<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>0x6a75646168</title>
    <description>A digital ronin who writes occasionally</description>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>New year, new site</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh jeez, what a &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; year it has been so far. I won’t remind you as to not
ruin the “vibe” of this post, however, let’s hope things improve/become stable.
If you’re one of the 22,000 readers of this “blog,” you may have noticed the design has changed… again.
“Why is that?” you might ask. Well, it started with me noticing that I had an
abundance of repositories on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kyoto-shift&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. 83 to be exact.
Granted most of these were private, sandbox repositories, so it’s not as though
I’m a &lt;em&gt;pioneer&lt;/em&gt;, creating “amazing” and “revolutionary” bits of software for the free world.
Honestly, I’ve treated GitHub as a sort of playground where I shitpost various
bits of code that I’ve most likely moved from my Thinkpad to my neglected WSL instance, or my
current—and probably doomed—Manjaro install (let’s hope this one lasts more than two weeks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kicker of this realization is that some of these repositories weren’t
actually mine. Which makes sense, right? Pull requests, issues, tickets, all of the
usual byproducts around contributing to open source software. However, it
occurred to me that I hadn’t contributed to most, if &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt;, of these projects.
That’s right, these forks were sitting on my account collecting digital dust due
to my horrible maid and open source contributer skills.
From the old, “1000+ commits ahead” JavaScript libraries to
the many underutilized webpack + babbel + dabble + gabble.io boilerplate starter projects,
my profile looked like the offramp of an old highway, littered with sadness and tiny shoes.
The funniest part was that I don’t actually write JavaScript.
It’s not my cup of tea, it doesn’t resonate with me, it doesn’t tickle my fancy,
it doesn’t… not get my goat(?) If you couldn’t tell, I’m not a fan. I know this
sound hypocritical coming from a guy who’s claims to fame were JavaScript-based projects.
Please don’t make fun of me on IRC using your 68%, farm-to-pcb key switch keyboard, slapping away at the 
various tmux and or i3 hotkeys you’ve graced your headless arch installation with.
I really hope you can forgive me on Twitter using your emacs-embedded web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, as I haven’t done any JavaScript development in many moons, I got to cleaning! Delete, confirm, archive, confirm.
My &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CTRL+C&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CTRL+V&lt;/code&gt; keys were worn like the armor of a Spartan after a long day’s battle. And finally, after wiping the various
fluids that &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; 68% keyboard accrued over the 20+ minute duel, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/kdXMdvhsvi0?t=48&quot;&gt;the peasants rejoiced&lt;/a&gt;.
No longer was I plagued by outdated libraries that I had no intention of contributing to in the first place.
No longer will I shudder while looking for that “stupid ass, poorly named” library that
is only three, nondescript letters long. My GitHub repository list is now at peace
and can rest for the time being. But there was a looming question, &lt;strong&gt;how did I get so many repositories in the first place?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that—with the “socialization” of open source software—I treated that innocent “fork” button
as a pseudo “super like” button. See something I like? FORK. Oh, do I want to save this for later? FORK.
Sure this could be dismissed as a naive user’s misuse of a version-control platform, however, I don’t think I’m the only one with this problem. I went through my followers/following on GitHub
and looked through each forked repository on their account. I recommend you do the same as filtering by forks makes
this very easy. To my surprise their repository list looked almost identical to mine. “300+ commits behind,” “0 commits ahead,” “last commit: 8 months ago,” I digress.
So why is there an overindulgence in the forking of repositories on GitHub? I think, and could very well be wrong, that many of us use the fork button as
a “save for later” button instead. This could be due to many factors, but in my case it’s because I:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Want to keep a copy of the repository for my own personal use/preservation;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan on actually contributing;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Am afraid that the repository might disappear in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure these reasons are okay on the surface, but these reasons are also—in my case again—a little disingenuous.
For example, one of the repositories I had on my &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;kill list&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was a JavaScript library that converted vertical scrolling
to horizontal. It was a very small library that I used in a project that never saw the light of day.
The only open issues were minor questions and documentation requests, all many years old. The last commit was around the same age.
My point is that the repository wasn’t worth a fork. Not that it wasn’t good, it did exactly what it said it would. But something to
keep for “personal preservation?” Yeah, I’m not so sure. Sure, maybe I was going to contribute to the &amp;lt;250 SLOC JavaScript library, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I think my inner data hording demon came out in full force when I forked that repository many years ago.
You see, I used to love having gigabytes of PDFs I knew I would never read, or tons of bookmarks
to articles I would “totally look at later.” I think we’re all like that to a certain extent.
We all like having the things we need, when we need them; especially developers.
No one wants to need that really awesome “stb_image.h,” only to find out the last mirror of it got deleted during the A.I singularity. 
But that’s not what the fork button is for, it’s meant for pull requests and issues and testing and the magical friendship gained through open source software.
&lt;strong&gt;If&lt;/strong&gt; you wanted to save this code for future you’s possible dire strait, you could use the beautifully simple “Download ZIP” button.
No muss, no fuss. Only the bliss of a perfect copy, converted to a format worthy of storing. I mean sure, that’s great and all, but then future you has to &lt;strong&gt;UNZIP A FILE&lt;/strong&gt;. Oh no, anything but that!
What if ApocalypticArch doesn’t ship with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tar&lt;/code&gt; because Richard Stallman’s GNU + A.I created malware that deleted it and any other file utility from every system known to man?! What then?!
Well then I guess you and your 952 repositories on GitHub can laugh at the robot overlords and their failed attempt to remove open source software from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All jokes aside I’ve now started to change my habits around forking and cloning things on GitHub. In fact, I’ve even moved most of my
“important” projects to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourcehut.org/&quot;&gt;Sourcehut&lt;/a&gt; as I like the idea behind it and the fact that they have first-class support for Mercurial.
But man, even though I’m tidying up my account and moving away from the platform… nothing felt greater
than watching that little chocolate bar thingy, knowing I had a completely separate copy on my account, untouched by the patches and commits of an angry BDFL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyways that’s why my blog/site looks different now. Hope you’re having a great day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/new-year-new-site/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/new-year-new-site/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gridicarus: Development Update #2</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Gridicarus is back and cleaner than ever! It’s been about a year since the last patch,
mostly because &lt;em&gt;(I thought)&lt;/em&gt; I liked how the project ended up and also couldn’t be bothered to update the dependencies.
However! One of the projects I’m working on could use Gridicarus’ help, so I decided to update it… and what I found was shocking! If you don’t care about the changes and just want to know what I’m talking about, &lt;a href=&quot;https://0px.moe/gridicarus/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/gridicarus-dev-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/gridicarus-dev-update/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tiny site update + plans for the future</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;여러분 안녕하세요! 오랜만이에요&lt;/strong&gt; –
Hey everyone, it’s been a while! If you’re an avid reader of my &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; active blog,
you might’ve noticed that there’s a few things going on. First off, the footer
is actually at the bottom of the website now. Incredible web design skill, I know.
Second, pinned posts! These will mostly be updates, but if I write an article
or something I’m proud of (in the near future maybe?), I’ll probably pin it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/tiny-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/tiny-update/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample Search is still alive!</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If you came here because you were looking for &lt;a href=&quot;https://0px.moe/samplesearch/&quot;&gt;sample search&lt;/a&gt;, don’t worry, it’s still alive. I just forgot to renew the domain name. Mostly because &lt;em&gt;sampled.pro&lt;/em&gt; wasn’t a very good name, and because it’s surprisingly expensive to renew .pro domains. Who would’ve thought a $0.99 domain name would cost $15 to renew?&lt;br /&gt;
In other news for sample search, it getting new features is kind of up in the air. I feel that it’s in a pretty good spot in terms of &lt;strong&gt;what it is&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;what it does&lt;/strong&gt;. I wouldn’t want to over engineer and take away from the site as a whole. I think the most I’ll be doing is removing the ad bar from the site since I no longer have to pay for a domain name and I only made about… $0.13 for the &lt;em&gt;entire year of 2018&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/004</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/004</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A quick update!</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow! It’s been around 2 (almost 3) months since I last posted here. This has
mostly been two-parts busyness and one-part life. However, I’ll be more active
very soon, and will be covering more interesting topics, as well as giving
updates to the projects I’m actively working on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/a-quick-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/a-quick-update/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gridicarus: Development Update #1</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Gridicarus is now stable at &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0.1.5&lt;/code&gt;! This is the &lt;em&gt;final&lt;/em&gt; “initial commit” for Gridicarus. I’ve gotten the documentation to a point where I’m happy with the framework, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; file is squared away, and I think it’s generally smooth sailing from here. Well, I use smooth sailing loosely… The stuff I wanna implement is not going to be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/gridicarus-dev-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/gridicarus-dev-update/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is this thing on?</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, this thing actually works! Needless to say getting this set up wasn’t the most fun thing I’ve ever done, but it’s done so I can’t complain. Anyways, welcome to the site! I intend to post a lot on here. From development updates for things I work on to music production tutorials and everything in-between. Maybe even some web design, who knows?!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/welcome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/welcome/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
